## Vipin KumarFeatured Resume

HR Manager seeking assignments in HR Management, Administration, Recruitment, Employee Engagement, Talent Acquisition, Training & Development, Manpower Planning, Performance Management, Compensation & Benefits, Organizational Development, Facility Management

Current Designation: Manager HR & Administration

Current Company: Bawana Infra Development

Current Location: Delhi

Pref. Location: Chandigarh, Delhi / NCR, Jaipur

Functional Area: HR / Administration / IR

Role: HR Manager

Industry: Construction/Engineering/Cement/Metals

Marital Status: Married

Total Experience: 14 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Highest Degree: MBA/PGDM [HR/Industrial Relations]

Key Skills: HR Manager, HR Management, Administration, Recruitment, Employee Engagement, Talent Acquisition, Training & Development, Manpower Planning, Performance Management, Compensation & Benefits, Organizational Development, Facility Management, Screening, Interviewing

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

ID: 59d67f6e197785c024Last Active: 17-Sep-20Last Modified: 16-Sep-20

Jump to SectionWork Experience | Education |

Summary

An HR professional having 14 years of rich and varied experience in the field of Human Resource Management. Handling entire gamut including HR, Industrial Relations, Administration, Liaison functions with a generalist profile and key focus on innovation in HR practices.

Work Experience

MS Bawana Infra Development Pvt. Ltd. as Manager HR and Administration

Jan 2020 to Jul 2020

Company Profile: - Construction work, Facility and maintenance work.

Job Profile:-

**Human Resources:** 

Recruitment; maintain data base, Screening resume, Scheduling of Interviews, Interview.

Freezing the final round of interview, reference checking & verification, salary negotiation.

Fixation of salary and designation, issuing of offer letter and appointment letter.

Exit interview and issuing Reliving letter & full and final statement of existing employees.

Standardized the joining formalities process of new employees (welcome circular, Introduction, Emp. Code, ID card, Bank account, Reference check etc.)

Making Induction of the new employees to make them aware of the organization policies, procedures, facilitating their interaction with different functional heads of the different departments.

Handling various issue/queries, complaints, grievances, disputes related to various HR departments.

Monitoring Selection process, Placement, Increments, Promotion.

Organize training programs on various levels of employees as per requirement.

Maintain Appraisal details (Half day, Leave day, late days, productivity etc.)

Salary processing, Distribution of salary & Wages Administration.

Personnel & Administration:-Time office, Security, Transport, Canteen Management, Housekeeping and General Office administration.

Statutory Compliance: -s

Obtaining/renewal of Labour license under CLA

Handling all labour cases in labour court.

Coordination with PF and ESI department.

Registration under BOCW act.

Handling all Liaoning like as Govt. department, Labour office, Industrial Health and Safety.

Bawana Infra Development as Manager HR & Administration

Jan 2020 to Till Date

NA

Ms Steiner India Ltd. (Part of HCC group) as Administration Officer Jun 2018 to Dec 2019

Ms Unitech Ltd. as Executive HR and Admin

Feb 2011 to Jun 2018

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: LLB (Law) from Ch Charan Singh University (CCSU), Meerut in 2015

PG: MBA/PGDM (HR/Industrial Relations) from Sikkim Manipal University (SMU) in 2011

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

MCA

Graduation